我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
需要特殊的快递吗
Need a special delivery
只需叫上Malo Korrigan
Just call Malo Korrigan
但不是免费的
But it's not free
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space
翻译、时间轴、后期：Bolshevik0
#1         西奥·道格德隆
Radio Tracer
Hey Malo. We've just entered the Spartax system.
嘿 Malo 我们刚刚到达Spartax星系
OK
好
Hey Jonas. Nap time is over.
嘿 Jonas 别睡了
Cut power on the photon drive.
把光速引擎关掉
You got it kid.
我知道了
Jonas, are you going to take me dancing tonight?
Jonas 你今晚要和我一起跳舞吗
And three...two...
3...2...
Careful there, Kwik Kwik.
Kwik Kwik 小心
Back to civilization at last.
终于又回到有文明的地方了
Lousy tinker.
蛮横的商贩
Watch out, will you, kid?
你小子给我注意点儿
Cargo isn't heavy but explosives can be pretty delicate
货物虽然不是很重 但是爆炸物可马虎不得
not to mention illegal.
更别说运输爆炸物是违法的
But the cops won't find our afraid if we explode.
但是我们爆炸的时候警察并不会察觉我们是否害怕
And what do you think the cops would say to that?
你认为警察会怎么看待这件事
It's a Zubaheul scooter.
这是个Zubaheul的小飞船
Zuba... what?
Zuba 什么
The Zubaheul, they're galactic nomads.
Zubaheul是太空中的游牧民族
Thought they'd all died out.
我还以为他们灭绝了呢
Jonas, this is a spaceship, Malo, not a roller coaster ride.
这里是Jonas 不要把宇宙飞船开成过山车 Malo
Malo, you just violated 35 articles of
Malo 你刚刚违反了第35条星际法律
the interstellar code in one fell swoop
关于突然俯冲的条款
Let's go check out our new cargo.
一起去检查一下我们的新货物吧
Hold it right there.
站住不要动
You'll want to be careful with that peashooter son.
你要小心你那个玩具枪啊
In case that you hadn't noticed Malo just saved your skin.
难道你没发现Malo刚刚救了你
I never asked him to.
我没向他求救
Now back off and let me go.
你们立刻后退 让我走
Hey whatever you say.
不管怎么说
if you want to join those Nimrods waiting outside.
如果你想加入到外面那些傻警察的队伍里
Then catch.
就拿着这个
Give that back to me now.
把它还给我
Calm down kiddo.
孩子你冷静点
My name's Malo Korrigan and this is my co-pilot, Cyana Baahra.
我名叫Malo Korrigan 这个是我的副驾驶Cyana Baahra
Sorry to break in your little conversation.
不好意思打断了你们的轻松谈话
But it seems our good friend agents Switch wants to pay us a visit.
但是看起来我们的好朋友探员Switch想拜访我们
I'm guessing he must be after this young tagger.
我猜他肯定是为了找这个年轻的嫌疑犯
Hand me and see if I care.
把枪给我 看我怕他吗
Then?
之后呢
That's not the way we do things on the Starduke.
这不是我们星爵号的做事方式
Agent Switch, what a pleasure to see you.
探员Switch 很高兴见到你
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么
Cut the charm Malo.
Malo 别客气
I'm after a delinquent for violation of the Aeronautics code
我以违反飞行法
and desecration of Consortium property.
和侮辱财团资产的名义进行搜查
Keep on eye, son. Sonny, watch your elbows.
眼看清楚点 脚踩轻点 小伙子
Cuz we're hold on explosives here.
因为我们这儿放了些爆炸物
Thank you my little friend.
小朋友谢谢你
Cyana, can you send the help please.
Cyana 你能帮我个忙吗
I'm giving officer Switch a guided tour.
我正领着探员Switch进行搜查
Jonas you all space dog,
Jonas你们这群星际流浪狗
it's a miracle to me how you keep this antique tub afloat.
你能让这艘古董飞船接着使用真是奇迹
Oh antique tub.
噢 古董飞船
He's just joking.
他只是开个玩笑
I hear you Cyana.
我听见你了 Cyana
3J, can you block highway DB West.
3J 你能把DB西高速公路堵住吗
Consider it done, princess.
没问题 公主
It's an emergency.
这是紧急情况
Salutation space tracers.
你们好啊 各位太空牛仔
A red alert from your favorite radio station.
你们最爱的广播电台传来一条红色警报
We need one of your brave souls to clog highway DB West in a hurry.
我们需要你们之中的一位立刻堵住DB西高速公路
Route DB West? Seems we're right on it.
DB西路 看起来我们就在这
West of Raptor 65.
在Raptor 65的西边
I bet my money that
我拿钱赌
the fellow tracer needs to cut your and suspension my local police.
有牛仔需要通过你的飞船来骗走这里的警察
Well well well, what do we have here.
诶诶诶 这有啥
Attention all units.
全体注意
Emerge immediately.
紧急情况
On Raptor 65 west, traffic jam for several miles.
在Raptor 65的西边 产生了数英里的交通堵塞
Agent Switch, I'm on my way.
这里是探员Switch 我在路上
Your talents are always in demand, agent Switch.
你的才能总是受到大家的需要嘛 探员Switch
See how our taggers good.
看看我们的嫌疑犯还好着没
Hey kid, what's your name?
小伙子 你叫什么名字
Sio Dolderan.
Sio Dolderan
Are you really a Zubaheul?
你真的是Zubaheul人吗
I'm the last of the Zubaheuls.
我是Zubaheul中的最后一人
Those who escaped the Consortium have disappeared.
那些逃离财团的人都消失了
They'll never ride the starways again.
从未在太空中出现过
If tags on tankers could bring 'em back
如果追回那些货运飞船能把他们带回来
I'd be the first to draw one.
我马上就行动
You're just a tracer.
你不过是个赏金猎人
What do you know my race?
你对我的种族有什么了解？
Not a whole lot I admit.
我承认我了解得不多
But I could write a book on prisons.
但我能写一本关于监狱的书
That's the difference between us.
这就是我们之间的区别
I'm too clever to let myself get caller.
我非常聪明 很难被抓住
No shop, Malo.
没啥好说的 Malo
What's that, Jonas?
怎么了 Jonas
He reminds me of someone.
他让我想起某人
I was never as stupid as that.
我可没他那么愚蠢
It took 12 years a prison to wise you up.
那是因为你在监狱呆了12年才变聪明的
Thank you, Malo.
谢谢你 Malo
Now we don't have to buy dynamite for the Consortium
现在我不需要为财团买任何炸药了
And charges so much the mines would close.
而花费太多会导致矿场破产
And the Consortium would buy them back from you at a bargain.
之后财团就能低价收购你们
If we're lucky.
如果我们运气好的话
Great missing.
重大遗失
One of the explosives is missing.
有块爆炸物不见了
See you.
再见
Tagging's not enough?
追逐游戏还不够吗
注:
dynamic adj.雄心勃勃的 和dynamite n.炸药 有共同的词根，<del>尬</del>双关
Then it's time I adopted a more dynamic approach.
这次我将采取一些更加有力的行动
This is Radio Tracer with a special message
这里是Radio Tracer 现在有一条特殊的消息
from Malo and his Starduke.
来自Malo和他的星爵号
Any one spots a young Zubaheul riding a scooter
有人如果看到一个年轻的Zubaheul人驾驶着一艘小飞船
can put in a call to this station.
可以马上通知本站
Radio Tracer.
Radio Tracer
There's no sign of him.
这儿也没有他的踪迹
Malo, Cyana!
Malo Cyana
Maybe Dolores know something.
也许Dolores知道点儿啥
Well hello handsome.
帅哥你好啊
It's always such a treat to see you.
每次见你都让人赏心悦目
You too, my dear.
你也是一样的
I heard all about your Zubaheul on the radio
我从电台那里听说了你们要找的Zubaheul人
but no one around here has seen him.
但是没人见到他
Hey 3J. This is *%^$%# on the Belladonna.
嘿 3J 这里是Belladonna号上的xxx
You mustn't be so glum, Malo.
你没必要这么不开心 Malo
The night is still young.
夜晚才刚刚开始
Who knows what will happen.
谁知道会发生什么
Not exactly a barrel of lots, tonight.
今晚没那么多麻烦
Why don't you dump this grouch
为什么不扔掉这个烦恼
and come with me to the Tiara.
到我的飞船上来呢
I need a co-pilot.
我需要一个副驾驶
And Mr. Korrigan isn't going to notice that you're gone.
Korrigan先生不会注意到你离开了
My dancing teacher Jonas would never forgive me.
我的舞蹈老师Jonas绝不会饶了我
All right. Let's go.
好吧 我们走
Hurry up! The tankers ready for boarding.
货船就要起飞了
It's when does the Consortium use tankers to transport its workers.
就是这个时候财团用货船运输它的工人
Since their shuttle broke down
因为他们自己的飞船坏掉了
stranding them here at the Consortium's expense.
让他们不得不用财团的价格支付费用
I'm listening Jonas.
我听着呢Jonas
He was spotted on the Consortium docks.
有人看到他在财团的船坞里
To the Consortium.
致财团
Consider this a down pin and all the damages you owe.
把这个当作你们欠下的账
All the passengers runway 5.
所有乘客到5号跑道集合
This zone is off limits.
此地禁止入内
Hand over your papers immediately.
立刻出示你的证件
I warned you guys.
我警告过你们的
Don't go sticking your nose in my affairs.
不要牵扯到我的事里
Kallu jewel Beck lahaa.
Where's the dynamite you stole?
你偷的炸弹在哪
No!
不
There are passengers aboard that tanker.
那个货船上有乘客
Not just robots but workers.
不是机器人 是工人
They're gonna die because of you.
他们将因你而死
But...but I didn't mean to.
但 但我不是故意的
It doesn't matter what you meant to do.
这和你有意与否无关
It's done.
已经完了
We're gonna have to work fast.
我们得快点儿
We've got time.
我们还是有时间的
Everyone's safe until the tanker goes into photon drive.
货船在打开光速引擎之前都是安全的
The tanker leaves our system.
货船要离开这个星系
Come on we don't have much time.
快来 我们时间不多
Jonas, prepare the Starduke for take-off.
Jonas 准备让星爵号起飞
And then wait for further orders.
然后待命
Cyana will explain.
Cyana会给你解释的
See you got a 4012 superdrive.
看起来你有一台4012号引擎
I installed it myself.
我自己安装的
Hey! What are you doing?
嘿 你在干啥
I'm sticking my nose in your affairs.
我在干预你的事务
I've never seen anyone but a Zubaheul drive like this.
我从未见过Zubaheul以外的人这么开飞船
The Dynamite's in the photon exhaust pipe?
炸弹埋在光速引擎的排气管里吗
300 meters from the open.
离喷射口大概有300米
没听清*&#%$#
（此处使用俄语片源对英语片源的瑕疵进行替换）
Did you guys listen?
你们听到了吗
Jonas sends me his regards.
Jonas跟我说了些数据
So, in my calculations,
所以在我的计算下
we have 2 minutes until the tanker goes to photon drive.
在货船打开光速引擎前我们还有2分钟的时间
There it is.
就在这儿
We get one try so don't blow it.
我们只有一次机会所以别搞砸了
Got it.
搞定
Malo! Your time's up. Get out of there.
Malo 你的时间到了 快离开那儿
Glad to see you back.
很荣幸看到你们都回来了
Well now seems there was some action in Sector 094.
看起来在第094区域发生过什么事
Routine.
例行公事而已
Dolores, are you still looking for a co-pilot?
Dolores 你还在寻找副驾驶吗
You've had a change of heart?
你改变了心意吗
Hmm.. of course he's not quite as cute as Jonas.
恩 当然他没有Jonas那么有趣
They can't have everything.
每个人都没那么完美
But I've had a chance to check him out as a co-pilot.
但是我已经检验过他作为副驾驶的资格了
He's pretty darn good.
他确实还不错
Well if he's good enough for Malo, there's only one thing to say.
如果对Malo来说他足够优秀 这就意味着
My new co-pilot, welcome aboard.
欢迎我的新副驾驶 请上船
Let's go princess.
我们走吧 公主
Time to rock and roll.
是时候摇滚了
It's the next best thing to find through the galaxy.
在宇宙中 这可是下一个最值得寻找的东西
Just ride and roll and ride and roll again.
我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space